All right well that was...get started my name is...I am
principle software engineer and microsoft and I'm join today with
...brown I'm a program manager on the office extensibility team over microsoft
...today we're going to talk about a developers guide to
...the cloud between office three sixty five and measure we think there's some really unique
ways that you can use the to services together in fact I think if you were to act look... talk to me
...doreen of times
...three sixty five is talked about as being a softwares...service and,
as your is a platforms a service actually think they're both...a service I really think of
...sixty-five that way in the different things that I can do with it in this session is really meant to
kind of highlight how those two can work strongly togetherif you just came
from a session I highly encourage you guys to remember to do your eval's and after this
session dear eval's feedbacks really important makes this conference better so that you
know, we continue to have great speakers and great content so highly recommend you guys feel
...your evaluations and you can quite possibly win a prize so
from a objectives and take away standpoint it really the goal of this is to
...developers to unique ways of using both asher and office three
sixty-five together we want to illustrate that there
are certain scenarios that...with asher and office re sixty-five
it would be almost impossible to deliver without combining those two services together and
then we also want to demonstrate how as your developers if you're already been doing a lot of things and
as your how you might be able to maximize those skills by tapping into office three sixty five in
the large number of subscribers that are out in across the globe
that use that service so from a take away standpoint I hope
that were successful today if you walk away understanding
that asher really provides the first-class experience for delivering office
...sixty-five extensibility as you're in office three
sixty five can deliver some really powerful scenarios and even
some hybrid scenarios I know that almost any organization regardless of how much they've
invested in delivering software through the cloud are also have things on
premises and will look at how we can work with some of that today with asher and,
then finally I hope that everyone walks away and I think we can achieve
...saying I didn't know that
blank could do that I think you regardless of how comprehensive knowledge you have across the
too I really think that will probably come up with at least something
you didn't know was a possibility so just a little bit about the opposite three sixty
five vision, you know, we have a vision of both being able to extend
a user experience and being able to get data out of or work with the
data that's in office three sixty five and again we think that asher...a key part of that so from
extending the user experience I might have an extension that I
build into office or a mobile app that connects
into different services there's a number of different ways that we can do that we can
extend user interface and then obviously there's a lot of data
that lives within that platform that I can go in tap into to light
up different applications and do more interesting things?
So, just a little bit to set the ground ...when we kind of
I vision and this session we kind of thought about a few different profiles of
users so what a highlight those...the first one is what I would called
the just general office three sixty five developer so this is someone that probably
has more experience on the office three sixty five maybe sharepoint
...than they do as your they might have some kind of limited experienced as
...maybe they've done some things will websites are databases
...maybe they're curious about how they might be able to leverage
cashmere to deliver more with office three sixty five and maybe expand their skills
to different platforms services yet quick show hands how many people here have
an...sixty-five subscription today right that also pretty much all of you good
...awesome the other type of person we thought that is not supposed to say
officer sixty-five developer that is...
would say general developer so one of the things that we're looking to
is there's probably a lot of developers that are looking at office three sixty five maybe your organization is
about to adopted or maybe you're just curious on how you might be able to do
...with that with that platform so we want to
expose some interesting things with
...sixty-five and how you might be able to maximize
your existing knowledge of badger to do more things maybe be able to
get into different monetize a shun things we maybe you have some apps you could sell or
admins that you might be able to ...and do more with and,
maybe you recognize that the developer opportunity is big
...and that brought you to the session and then finally we have kind of the other maybe
your architecture decision maker looking to better understand the...the cloud
...software vendor that has products that have
a productivity focus or maybe you just looked on the conference schedule
...buzz words like...office three sixty five...the keno actually...session that's right well it
...that last person is you I have one slide the kind of help out with that so here is
a cloud and...surface and a hollow lens?
...cross-platform and a picture kitten...to kind of get some buzz words
and exciting things out of the way so with that I'm going to turn it over to
...to talk a little bit about...the yes so we've layout kind of the goals of
this session in who we to intends talked to before but,
how are we going to actually while you with all the integration that we're doing right basically what we plan to show you
today is since most of you have officer sixty-five subscriptions and you are using office
three sixty-five how can you take this tendency all the information about your
...connected here as three-d subscription where you can gets more resources on how
...eighty works and then walk through a bunch of what we personally think are really
interesting features and capabilities inside of the asher platform and how we can connect those to
...sixty-five to make your
...data really do some cool stuff as well after that I'm sure you hotel questions
...going to blow your mines and we'll go from there one thing I'd say on that on the list
of the keep features here and this is actually a little bit there's a few different things that we're going to
...here ...do some things...apps...but what I would say is that there's,
there's tons of different services within office within asher and,
we really had...kind of pick what we think hit some popular scenarios so,
I think that's what you'll find is that some of these things in here we fitch we picked strategically
because we hear a lot from customers hey I want to be able to do this and...services help
...differ something they're interested in that we haven't covered we'd love to hear about it
maybe hear about what scenarios that you're trying to solve we can work...things like
...dot com or sessions in the future?
All right so the first thing you need to do in order to develop for either
asher office or anything in general
it's actually set up your developer environment when it comes to this first you need an
officer sixty-five...can either get this through the three free three-day
trials you can get this...get a thinking...free year msdn of
...msdn subscription or you can join the developer program that we
have going on down on the first-floor you get a free year of an office three
sixty-five dev tenant if you sign up and you go through the
introductory programs then you need to sign up for your own windows as your subscription a quick show
hands how many people here are msdn subscribers.
How many people here know you can get a hundred-fifty free
...of asher credits every month?
How many people here use that build...apps already awesome okay so what's the...the
...are slowly going down so the session will be a useful but it's good to know so,...go...
app then you need to set your administrators so that you can actually edit the data
...is applications working in your tenant and then we'll show you how to use
bs twenty fifteen to actually get an app working inside of your office...sixty-five tenant?
Right so with that I'm going to switch over.
To my pc here.
And, on the screen right now I have where you can get a
...thirty trial of
...sixty-five if you scroll down to the bottom here you can actually get
this free trial but based off the show...the fact that this takes a while to provision
probably about ten minutes so we're just going to skip over this and procedure the next step here.
Great so the next after that we've go to the
windows as your subscription that I have as we talked about earlier you can login to
your msdn subscriptions page and get access to visual studio your free as your credits
all of that it sounds like most of you are aware of that but that's great.
Of...one thing really quickly is if you don't have an...your subscription and you don't have in
...in you can go and it requires a credit card you can create
an as your account just to be able to go in and manage as
...active directory now you won't...cost anything
now if you start provisioning other things you'll start getting bills but just to do the asher ad part
we're trying to make that better over time you'll be able to do more that directly from
...administration but, just for those that don't fall into those buckets of
...msdn subscriber someone...a measure account jan...also get ten
...websites to see and star provisioning in doing some trial work but anything
serious does require a credit card with actual money on it...so here I
...my as your management portal and you can see that there are many different items here that you can use to
...applications will touch on a few these today and
I'll show you where they are inside the portal but for now we're just going to look at this active directory.
Every office three sixty five tendency hasn't
asher active directory associated with it and all users in apps and information about
the tendency resides in this portal that you can take a look at so we'll hook up
a blank tendency to this address description but first let's take a look at what
...looks like when there's actual data inside.
So, here I've got my own msdn subscription my own...
a added to my as your account you can see here I have a whole bunch of options run users in groups
and apps and what we really care about here is the list of applications
...associated with my tenet so these are all the apps that I've built these are all the apps
...I found either, you know,
on somebody's website or through the rem a groups a really cool and
that consented to use right so I can go look at the ones...own so things...built?
Right and that's just click into...see what it looks like so I'm just going to take a look
...this gps viewer here it was just a quick demo are used but I
said a bunch of stuff in it and you can see.
That the app is multi tenant which means that I've set it
up to work on basically anyone who logs into the website
if I wanted to just build a line-of-business app
...a single tenant but I've also said that I want to
give this application permissions to access office three sixty five and in this case I just give it
access to sharepoint rate to read and write users files
but I can also add applications dynamics our
...anything and will touch on a few of these during our demos and how you can
connect the your apps in your data together to do some cool stuff but this is how you give the apps
permission to actually edit the data inside of office now let's say have
...at my tenant I just want to put this in here I'll go to new?
App services directory.
Great so I...say hey I have
...tendon...I'm going to custom create this.
And, because already exists you already have my office subscription...going to use
...existing directory and says you need to sign up blah-blah-blah already signed up
great.
...while we're at it.
This is a...you're not going to get much out of the top of my password.
Shipment password in here.
Right so now we're saying do you want to add this
tenant to your microsoft as your subscription do you want to be able to edit and add new applications
...your users in here I want to.
Right and that's it super simple super easy if you haven't done this already
are highly recommended just for the purposes of knowing what's going on in your tendency
...I can sign out of my office account log back into my
...description you'll actually see the tenant right their.
Rates...log...back in.
It's going to take a little while that's fine.
And, we get back to this page.
...load...oil so now we have the application attitude tenant
...can actually create applications are visual studio that we could hook into our own
a-z sixty-five tendencies right and you can do this manually
...the portal you can create a new applications sawyer resource
id do all of that but instead let's these a...that does...all for
us so what I have here is visual studio twenty fifteen release candidate it was recently
...ticket titties...some with...and we're going to use this to create and app and deploy it to
...website so I'm just going to say I want and sp dot
net web application...doesn't really rather with the
name is and we'll go ahead here.
There's two important parts to the setup process that you need to really know about to be
able to authenticate with a...sixty-five single sign on.
First I want to thank in my work in school account the
coyote sixty-five tendency here and I'm going to say I want this to be used by multiple
organizations this is the multi tendency that talk about early deal...microsoft
commas my own domain and I will give us app permissions to read my directory data so
it knows who is trying to sign...added is actually user inside of the tenant.
So, we're going to let this sit under...
The second thing that is important is an want to deployed this to
...website so the...website is workloads hosted its
...lives and it prevents us from having to sort of is
...or patchy server...anything we just click if you buttons and we're done.
So, in this case it just gives us a name that it
...unique we want to be the west us...in california.
And, while that's going we'll go back to the portal here.
And, show you that app.
So, there's control so that was the tendency that we just added
...click I can click into it and actually see all the different things here.
Let's pop back over...visual studio.
...a little while the create the web app is adding the
tech information to measure ed and you can see here is working a
little bit on creating the measure web app inside of the cloud.
So,...doing that let's take a look at.
The adder india authentication configuration you need to actually get this out-of-work
...so in visual studio twenty thirteen you would see this in the ad connected services
box when you install the officer sixty-five tools are visual studio but in twenty fifteen
...move this out into its own menu and you can go in here we want single...on we want to use are
of...sixty-five accounted accesses app here's the coin id
and redirect uri and I will set that to.
The web application.
Five six nine two dot
measure websites dot net which is where we will deploy all this data to.
And, that's my clients secret great that's on tv early.
So,...replace a bunch of files for us.
You can see here we can just published this web application to this web
...dot net.
So, let us it for a little while.
In the meantime let's go to office three sixty five and see where
this apple appear once we can
...to existing within our tendency so we go to
...the office dot com.
It'll probably login.
And, we'll see at the top...what we call the app launcher and the app launchers the listing of
...all my applications live inside of office rates you can see here I've
got mail-in calendar and people in one...all the apps that your
...of today we'll see here I also have like this web application and that is
...I previously consented to so if I go.
To one-world location.
I can just run this here.
There's currently a bug in visual studio where if you publish it without doing a bunch of
workit will fail out on...
redirect...to show you just from my local machine I will log in with my...sixty-five account.
And, this is where...me hey...in for the first-time to this to this
application do you give it permission to actually access everything you do
in this case we want to read directory data and login to the app
...I'm okay with that so let's just accept.
And, it'll do its work will grant
the consent the first-time is a little slow but when we get back
and actually show you some information right so that was it that was what
ten seconds maybe most of it be talking we went from no code no app nothing hosted in
the cloud...actually being able to authenticate and cali...sixty-five api
in fact if I go to the user profile page which is some predetermined
code that the visual studio...makes for us week this will actually call the unify
api is that we announced earlier?
In build...it displays the data from my tendency as
...naturally so from here.
That's you're pretty much good yourself.
Right so every app...you...adder every at the
...the connect office three sixty five a uses these core concepts.
So, attractive
directory applicationswe talked about this is where your third-party information your
metadata is stored of to use one to use it applications
that access to multiple three sixty five services you have an app the
...to your exchange email your sharepoint sites your office three sixty five groups and then
also standalone applications that you just want to authenticate to office
...maybe you're...the does not even need anything in
...sixty-five but you don't want to implement your own authentication you can use it for this too.
The second concept we just went over to review is these are these actually
...apps and this is just the service for hosting all the data in the
...we talked about so just you create this app it does it
all deployment for-you visual studio you
...f five in publish it right there very simple very straightforward.
So, I'm going to passes...simple stuff building on top of all this, yeah, so,
I'm not going to I'm actually going to need some audience participation brando pretty elaborate demo that's going
to use a number of different as your services so in just a moment I'm going to put upq r
coding of a web url maybe some of your already,
already saw it but what I'm going to do is let me bring a bring up
my phone here so this is just a really simple mobile website and what it's going to do it's going to read
your user agent and it's going to decipher what device
and browser you use it also watcher location we're going to actually see what type of
devices the most accurate with gps indoors just for fun but,
...some really cool sharepoint things with this...submit mine?
Here and you should give me a little prompt says thank you for submitting so now I'll go back
to powerpoint side really quickly and let you guys do the same so if you just
go to bitterly are bit...slash...three sixty five build...a
...encode here you can do this alongside of me so what we're
going to do is go through a number of different scenarios that I here are really popular with
cussed customers are asking for hey we're moving in the cloud we need to do a number of different
things so we're going to go through a couple of different services and see how that might dub
tail into...solution that you might want to deliver within your organization
sofa everyone had a chance to see this I'm going to move on so the first thing we're going to look is
measure storage...now as your as a number of different ways that I can
q data so the scenario here is I actually the
dated the your submitting through that website I actually need to do a lot of processing
on it behind-the-scenes I don't want...sit and wait for that so what I did is when you
went...submitted your form I basically just through the data on a
q and let it keep going right so we're basically queuing updated there's a
number of scenarios and office three sixty five there are great for
...a really good one is in things like sharepoint online provisioning a
site I might want to submit some like a can
like the configuration of the type of side I want maybe
that template some different options and then kind of move on and then once
it's done maybe...sins me an email so that's the type of thing we're doing here so we're going to
look at and as your storage q which uses the asher blob storage
out there's other things like service plus...there's a there's things like event
hubs that we can use queuing type of mechanisms with this one
is a little bit more specific in that really it's the idea is to be able to drop-off messages and
have a consumer receive those we're going to really use this for things where I might want
some sort of worker role behind-the-scenes
ob we can do some really interesting hybrid scenarios here I
can have something on premises listen on this q and be able
to do processing so it starts doing some really interesting ways that I
could communicate through firewall by innocence polling for things in that
to you...there's alsothis one is it going to guarantee order so the as
your storage...don't have like a five-fold type of model if you wanted something like that
there are things that service...use you could use but...I picked this storage
...very specific reason in that we're going to go into next is something called
a web job a web job can actually be triggered
...this q so as soon as something it's the q my web job can pick it up and
move on so there's a lot of great examples for this but let me really quickly
jumping decoding search show you out easy it is to write to a...
So, we're going to visual studio here and I had this at
...this is what you submit your data to just now it was basically a
...a web api in point and what I do is I'm going to establish a connection to
my cloud storage account so the first thing I did when I when I set
up this project is I added a new get package for as
...storage so if I were to go into this project here which is
my web project and look at my new get packages and this is I'm going to
put this entire solution out on get hubs you guys can put down and take a look at it but if we look at the installed
solutions one of the things that you'll find in here maybe there's a lot of things?
There is at the very bottom is asher windows address storage that's going to allow me to write to a
...or do anything with blob type storage so I'm getting a client that I'm
going to work with...I'm basically establishing a connection to the q and
then I'm basically saying created if it doesn't already exist so...to validated that
he was present and then what I'm going to do is go out here and just stick that data on
a serialized is...into the q so let's see how many we've collected
...all refresh this is just as
your storage explores of free tool you can download and let's see do a
little repression see how many items so quite a few here...queued up I have nothing
processing is right now and that's what we need to do next is we need a process all of these message?
So, that was storage...the way we're going to
processor messages with a web job the this is one
of my favorite features within windows asher so
...always had the concept of roles like worker roles but a role typically has a
lot of overhead it's not cheap web jobs are just a component of an as
your web app measure website so as doreen said most users get
ten free...websites well guess what you get ten free web jobs
so you can use these web jobs and it's so easy to use of
...basically just a consul application zip up and you go place out in
asher so these are great for background processing anytime that you need to do
scheduled processing continuous processing already sort of trigger
base processing and we'll take a look at this so there's a lot of great
examples if you've ever followed what we're doing around our office three
sixty five patterns and practices there's some really great patterns that
they've developed around leveraging some of these web jobs for things
that timer jobs in sharepoint or maybe need to do some sort of other background processing
another service like exchange of I had an executive assistant come to me the other day and
say every time we do on these conferences I've to go send hundreds of
emails out to different partners from the executive they needs to be from their
in-box and...a great kind of
background process that we could do with office three sixty five so let's take a look at our
webm job and how we're going to process that automatically...of our q?
Actually I'm a...you...all right so you notice that in
my solution explore I've a bunch of different projects but,
you can ci this web job project and it is literally just a consul
lap project there's nothing special about this it's just a normal consul
application so I'll go ahead and go into my consul application so
here you can see the typical main that kind of kicks things off and one of the things that
I added in...there's a new get package for web jobs
so the first thing that I did was come out here and say I want to add that...jobs
new get package so that I can work with web jobs easily
...of the things that gives me is this web job hosts where what I'm saying
is I want to run continuously so this is going to basically when I when I go
...upload this into asher this is going to
this consul applications going to stay running forever and,
one of the things that it also gives me is the ability the ability for
...something...using a q trigger.
So, if you look here I this thing called process
attendees and the very first thing that I'm saying
...here is I want to trigger this...and something getting added to the
q and I just put in here the q names so if we were to go back to address
storage explore you can see that the name of my q is a...dq
so what this is saying is when we go and put this out here it's going to listen on this...
anytime a message comes out we're going to call this method here
so really simple the cool thing is when I'm ready to actually deployed...to asher
all I have to do is come out to the folder words that.
Grab either the release or the debug I'll just add debug here.
I'm going-to send it to is zip file you can see...basically I just created a zip file of
my entire project and I'm going to go and
upload that intowindows asher so if I were to come out here to measure account.
Here's my websites you can see that
...under the website area of the portal and,
if you go into website there is this tab for web jobs and that's really what...
concentrating on here is the web job component of this.
And, I can simply come out here and uploaded that zip file and then I
have a choice on what I want to do I want to run it continuously job want
...run on-demand or do I run it on want
to run it on schedule it actually provides a scheduler so you can actually coming here fewer building
a timer job and sharepoint you could say I want to run every night at two am and, it gives you
that ability to really cool concept here that's free with these web jobs
and it's really cool when combined with the storage q so?
I'm not quite ready to upload this because there's another really popular
scenario that I want to fit into this and that is once I start adopting all of
these cloud services what if I...I still need ted to work
with some data that runs on premises some legacy data how does office three
sixty five reach into on premises something that might be behind
of firewall and be able to work with
that data and there's another service that we're going to look at that's going to make that possible.
So, we're going to look at something called a cashmere service
...relayed I'm curious out of...curiosity who here is
work with remote events which sharepoint remote events a couple
...so if you've ever done remote events one of the things you apt is
set up is you have to go configure a service
...connections dream and what that is not to go too deep but
abode event basically call it causal website or I'm sorry
...service...for office three sixty five?
To call your local host machine.
It basically sets up a connection through the service...so what this is a service
...relay is a bidirectional communicationmechanism
where you have two points that are listening on the bus and they can both
...messages to the bus and reading messages off of it and it can
be done synchronous silly so I can go and I could call basically
a service on premises behind a firewall from
within the cloud is a great scenario five legacy services that I want
to securely connect into or if I have certain like nat job considerations
for some on premises data is really great scenarios that we can enable here.
What I'm going to do is I'm going to set up a quick basically a quick
service that's going to run locally here and I'm behind all kinds of firewalls
on behind the don't have a static ip and,...
as you're still going to be able to call my local machine because of that service
bus so we'll take a look at this here?
So, going back to my solution I've a couple things I want to point out one is I have this
thing called legacy service and this is just basically
it's my it's my a mock-up of what like some legacy
service that you might have is the key for
you to do this service bus is you do need to
...whatever service you have behind a...in point so,
what I simply...could simply call another service once you do it but,
ultimately that's how you configure this so in my legacy service?
You can ci this thing called a geo service what this geo services
going to do it's going to calculate the distance between
your devices latitude and longitude and what I know the latin
longitude is of this room so we'll see how accurate your device
was indoors based upon the data use...mid-year that's all it does
right this could do anything it could be going out and calling sap may be or some other,
you know, line-of-business application that you have on premises service
...a great example how you might be able to leverage that the one key thing
is that both this legacy service and are web job
we're going to have in common is they're going to have a contract they share and that's
...wc of contract and it's simply just...if I go
out here here's our interface called get distance and it just defines
what the parameters are so they both know the right way to talk to each other so this is
define both in the service here you can see implements
that I geo service and then it's also implemented in my web
...so that it knows the right message and how that that's going to communicate the between each
other so this legacy app it basically is to
low consul application where I'm going to set up my in point to the service
...and just say host dot open that basically says I want to start listening on the service
bus and I'm actually do the exact same thing on the
other end where I want to go and call into that service buss if I go back to
my web job so again what you're looking at here is behind the firewall this
is my legacy on premises service that's going to listen for things
talking to it overall my web job?
I have you can see the very first thing I'm doing
...process attendees is going get the distance were passing
...indian get the distance if we look at what that distances doing
it's again setting up a endpoint into the service bus I'm
setting my connection information to that and then I'm just calling the service so
I'm saying channel dot get distance and that's going to call that synchronous sleaze so I'm
going to...and on premises service synchronous
flea with this data.
So, I think we're about...actually start processing some data through
this application so let me go and let's uploaded give it a
...it works actually the first thing I'm going to do is start my on premises service so
we go over here and all I did was just building so if I just did a
audio rebuild year and I just went to the been folder.
And, we'll start the consul application and
here it goes.
It'll tell me okay it's listening now so it's basically waiting for people to
call it and that's the input points that sb is so
the service bus prefix that we have that in point so we're listening on this service
bus right now they
...secure keys so this is a very secure way of doing things it's like think of it
is like an application secret that we're going to be able to
...work on this with now before I upload my
web job you might say where's office three sixty five and all this
you've been doing some kind of cool things and as your but I really haven't seen anything on the
...sixty-five side well once I get my distance
back what I want to do is shovel that data into a sharepoint list.
that brings up some pretty cool things that we haven't really disclosed yet so you may be
hearing hopefully this will be something that you're hearing for the first-time we as
of this week now support making...app only call.
Into the office three sixty five api up until now it's always guided operate
as a user everything had to be in the context of the user but now if I were to go out to
where I've defined my applications...this little thing that's called the sp
...only app you can see that I can specify.
Application only permission so this was not an option until this week for sharepoint
online we could do with exchange but not sharepoint online what's cool
is it if you work...sharepoint the past you knew that sharepoint you could do and
...only call with a
cs this is way more secure in my opinion because it's actually going
to make the communication with a certificate so what I do is
...once I specified is actually at the download my
And, this is an example of an agile manifest and what you'll see is
actually have to go put in a basic
...for encoded certificate right this is actually the public key
of a certificate that I'm putting out inside a badger
there's some great documentation on how to do this but ultimately my
...job now without having to do anything with average new
insider sharepoint is going to be able to top into sharepoint to
add list items so this does a couple of really powerful things you as
anonymous users are writing to my sharepoint site right now and,
you're doing it through and as your ad secured
application which I think is a pretty cool pretty cool thing the
other thing that you may not have known this is another this maybe you walk away saying I
didn't know it had that sharepoint actually has a geo column of you guys
knew that but, you know, you create columns in a sharepoint list you can create single-line of
...dates all different things actually geo column but it's hidden so what I do
is I went created a geo column through our shell in sharepoint online and,
the reason we added hidden is you have to specify a
been key so I'll just show you here that you can go copy this down really quick and you could use
mine probably but I just did a really quick thing that says go what register that
being maps key as a property on my website and then go and add
a geo column field to my list pretty simple outpost this on
a blog but we're we've collected all this data from you we've...by calling
in on premises service now we're going to go stick that into sharepoint that has
a nice geo column the store all this so because you're...esri...you could maybe
send an email out via exchange or...a group or something else, you know,
longer have to worry about being in one particular workload which is kinda so one thing I will show you here really
quickly let me go back to my timer job we looked at where I was calling get distance let's go
...because the other option right after I get my distance you'll see the second thing is
add to sharepoint and
let me just show you there's only a slight difference in how I work with this using these
certificates than a normal...normal usually go to no off low...redirect
them to login that comes back...the code I go and get an access token obviously there's
no user here it's a service so it's going to be a little bit different so if we go
down here to add to sharepoint I'm going to do some typical things like get
an authentication context but the very next thing I need to do is go
get the private key of that certificate so as
your knows about my public key my
...job that's actually going to go make the call knows about the private key and that's what's going to
allow them to make this happy handshake to do things so you can see wanders
...basically getting the bites of the certificate and
then I'm creating a x five nine certificate that ongoing to pass
...to get an access token so you can see here...get this thing called a client
assertion certificate and then when I get my access token which is right
year acquire access token bypassing my sharepoint site
and that certificate information so this is probably you if you've kind of
played around inside of this is a dal that's providing this the...
active directory authentication libraries if you messed around with the authentication
context before you may have seen this override
this overloaded on the acquire access token and this is where it comes
into play when I'm calling into these api as with our user I
provide that certificate after that it's just normal share points if you look down
here I'm basically putting the token on my header and I'm making
...posting the data just using normal ...no data so I'm just doing
a post to my list just to show you there's no smoke and mirrors here are my
lists and up I go to attendees I have nothing?
And, the deep breath let's see if this works so we'll go out to
my job I'm a call this a specific thing because I want to look at in the logs.
So, go in...that.
I'm going to upload that zip file that's all I'm doing is uploading zip file.
And, I'm going to specified two-run continuously.
So, I'll go ahead and say okay so that's going to go
...can...the cool thing about this is it as the concept of logging is
well these web jobs you can go see the consoles you can do consul
outright line throughout and you can see exactly what happened so
that allows updated this but let me go in and refresh this.
And, may been so long get mhairi login.
So, it's running or it's actually stop right now.
Actually may have already been it may already done it happens really quick what's going...attendees.
...have attendees...sitting in front of us let's see if they're in my...
So, they should be in the attendees list which...other place now.
...cfive an error.
Getting...we access token.
Calculate...distance, yeah, so,
I think...a overpowered this by doing it all at once so,
let me you really should have this running so it's doing a little...time I'm just going to refresh this and...one through.
Ago...and say submit it goes
...let's go back here will look at it on the q there's a few
...if you guys are...is with me.
...fill...up...
Job be nice.
The question is the...uk sensitive because you have a lower-case
q if where I had it it's not some places it is so there
we go we have some attendees here...that's weird some of them have no user agent
...of you guys are blocking or dunes and weird that's in there so we...iphones have...android device
and here you see how it a process these in here I'm not sure what happened the first-time that was kinda
weird but and, this will continue to go process items through is we get more and more but,
ultimately we you know, it basically
kind of process as we might expect here we have a number of different distances too I notice that
the ones that didn't get didn't have a user agent string have kind
...weird distance by go into one of these that...that geo columns that actually
...pretty cool that's something that's out-of-the-box and sharepoint online you may not have known these geo columns
...show you exactly where it is from the lat long standpoint so,
pretty cool from that so there's one other thing that's kind of neat that I have going on
here that I've talked about...is...logic gap
...listening for items being added to the sharepoint list and I
want to workflow on it and specifically as they get added
I want actually maybe post...messaging the gamer I just one that I picked but,
ultimately there's all these great little connectors that you can use in logic apps inside
a badger so that's the next thing that I want to talk about...about these logic apps
...is that although we're showing you posting this t amr you can actually create your own logic
...connectors...into your own custom processes so don't limit yourself you
just what's available in the store today you can build your own...to your own custom
workflows absolutely so this is a fully manage
...a service to automate some sort of business process already...you might have some sort
of tricky integration that goes from maybe one system to another which really
...for workflow type of scenarios right I know that sharepoint has a concept
of workflow but this is kind of a higher level if I want to workflow across a number of
different systems there's a great way of building these and orchestrating them within these logic
apps so in this case the example I'm doing is basically
a social posting manager it's, you know, I might want to put something in here maybe I want to
post-it to multiple different social channels or maybe I want to per vision do some sort of
provisioning through this that basically touches a number of different things the
...is these logic gaps as long as you're using one of the connectors that's already available their code
...I don't have to deal with any sort of code so,
let's take a look really quickly at building a logic app that might
connect into office three sixty five?
I've already created one ahead of time and this is my and we can actually see
that it's been working so here a second I'll go to gamer actual just go and do that...go to
...you're really fast here's the...you could see I have all of these postings that
was made through my logic app and if you zoom in on these you can see what it's done it says
...just register using windows and
ie browser here's one that used chrome here's an android that used
to chrome browser and you can see it was created from a logic
app so this is real the no-smoking mirrors here was one-minute...that this occured and,
as you guys add more they'll,
they'll keep posting here is incredibly easy to get started with
these logic gaps so let's go and create one maybe from scratch?
So, I'm here in the as your portal if you go under new they're under...in mobile
...weird place for them to show up...web...mobile what you'll see is
...this option to create a logic at and we'll just call this demo.
Budget app.
And, then I can say create so this will take a moment ago
in provision now logic gaps can be kicked off manually
...jobs...I can mainly...those off or I can kick them off based on some sort of
trigger so the first step what I create this logic app is to determine
...what I'm going to do is I'm going to specify that I want to use a trigger now
fights select trigger it's going to ask me what do you want to trigger
this logic at the coping is I can go and pick a connector that has the concept of
a trigger which is what I'm going to be able to do here...sharepoint
online so this all it takes a moment for these things to provision.
Looks like this is almost done actually while we're waiting on...isthere's
a show the other one player at it because they do take a few minutes.
Actually there is done ok so here's our
...and you can see there's a little getting started wizard that kind of talks about like what steps you
need to do but the first step is really to set up the trigger you can see
here's the trigger or action and this will bring out the landscape of what I can do now
I've preset up some connectors you can see them over here on the side I've
set up sharepoint online I've...
humor but let's say that I hadn't set those up just to show you what that
processes I can go visit the marketplace and there are hundreds of connectors
already there and as doreen said you can make your own connector so you can see there's twitter
connectors dropbox sharepoint server so on premises sharepoint I can do
office three sixty five which is really exchange if you read the details of it if I wanted to send
e-mail or read calendar do different things like that it's
in here and you can search for different things so all search for sharepoint.
here is that sharepoint online connector and you can see if you read the details of it tells you
know, I can trigger this based on a document being added new items being added things
being updated there's a lot of different things I can trigger based upon and ultimately
what I do is I give it the site and the list that I want to listen on and it just happens
for me so if we go back to our app let's go ahead and pick
maybe a predetermined connector that already have
...and coming here and also like the sharepoint online connector you can see
...connecting to the app will ask me to authenticate to sharepoint
online of already configured the url of my sharepoint online site but it's going to say you need
authorizes so...launch this dialog.
And, login.
It will access it as you.
Or whatever user you specify your open wrong password.
We go now it's going to go and say how for how do you want this to trigger and
selma say when people add new items in
that attendees list I can specify frequency?
So, I will warn you that depending on your licensing
...you can'tpossibly do these every second so if you see if...
second it's going to say nah not with your licensing I can do I think up-to-the-minute
that's...as often as I can do so every minute I can go out there I can specify
I don't where the cool things that can do is move it from the list to
...archives so I know that it's processed it which is what I implemented so actually
...archive list that moved all of these two and, I can even specify a view...finally
want specific columns so if I if I say okay here what we'll see is
it shows me all the columns in that list these are outputs now that I can use
another step so it's very easy to configure these...steps what I'll do is I'll go and,
maybe saved this?
And, then what I can do is come in and this is a little bit could you I think they'll fix it but in order for me to add
additional steps side to come back into it so I now have might trigger but I
wanted to communicate with yam so ago...edge...to this?
And, that will be that next step so I'll go and authorizing the
amr and what it'll do is it'll say when you post
...message but the cool thing is in my message I can
use all of the data from the list item that was created in sharepoint so I could say
...you zoom in here a new message
...our pick the device I can just come out
here and say input the device and it puts kind of a syntax in here that the app
uses that's it these things are incredibly easy to build a very powerful
...so just...you've already seen the output of these is you've seen kind of
them posting into gamer let me show you that they've actually move them from this
list of our to refresh my list year there's some more that have been added I think it kind of caught up
finally but also I have things in my
archive...these are getting moved that archive constantly?
So, pretty cool stuff I wanted to end with one last thing just for fun we collected
all this data another really powerful thing about as
...directory and what we call common consent is that I can connect into other
services that...part of oper three sixty five I can authenticate once maybe
connecting to sharepoint maybe exchange maybe one note but there's other things one of those
it's really cool that we have is things like
dynamics crm but I'm going to actually play with our by I'm
...send all this data now medical read-out of a sharepoint list and I'm
...send it into our...I can analyze it and I just
...another little consulate to do that here it you can see
it's doing normal things it's getting setting my headers to...a sharepoint then it's
going in building a our by table getting the data and basically sticky in
a our by so here's my our by and I'll just refreshment page I'll
see how incredibly fast this actually operates you can see my datasets
...on the side I'm going-to go ahead and press play?
you can see it's already created my build attendees dataset and now I can coming
here and play with this and we could do things like let's look at may be device and distance.
...take a second for it.
One distance...and we can see which one is the moguls
...chrome is not the most accurate so what you're seeing on one side there is distance
looks like...other and safari do better than chrome with it and then that does blanks I'm not sure
...up at the blanks but pretty cool I can bring this full-circle and I can start
connecting in the many other services great so go back here?
That's office as your rate was...cool how you could take all of...from office
...any real like an hour literally we actually went from beginning to end data
in sharepoint data...our by so what we want you to do is actually takes
analogy learn the session...build your own naps could tell us about these app...post on the
...sixty-five yam are group...us or do whatever you want some helpful links to help
...started...office dot com is the
number one resource for learning how to build apps in
...fifty-five platform right so we have getting started experiences links
to sign up for our developer program which again we'll give you a whole bunch offree stuff to
help get started here in addition the advert documentation and...up
...questions about the
address specific portions of the presentation that's also a great place to start?
In addition there's several
sessions that are related to a lot of the things we touched on today and they'll go to much
further detail than what we had time to do so in particularly the logic
...session will go into a very deep dive about how this all works integrating web apples
...sixty-five that was earlier this afternoon with the
recordings available if you have some issues debugging your demos like we did
a klout authentication troubleshooting will be helpful for you...this session will be useful but these
...especially picked out.
I mentioned...presentation but we are launching the offices sixty-five
developer program with this build conference if you go down to the first-floor of the
center you'll see a whole bunch of us...these blue booklets.
And, what happens is your several different things probably takes about an hour tops
if you complete all of them will give us some resources on web development and free office...
Or have an answer questions...get any concerns that you have particulate
even after the conference if you decide that you want to do this...dot office dot com slash
...program is where you can get started really developing prophecy sixty-five
...wire build...figures to join the dev
programming get a whole bunch of freed of a dot office dot com sway?
Check out the...talks on the first-floor I think we have a few more tomorrow but
you the schedule is down on the first-floor bile of our blues.
And, finally sign up for the program build some cool
...let us know what you think...make some cool stuff.
And,...also important great thanks everyone.